JESSICA CHIU

FRONT-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



PERSONAL SUMMARY

Vancouver-based developer focused on accessible, responsive, and user-friendly software design who would love to join your team. Professional experience in a start-up environment with a proven ability to take initiative, prioritise tasks to meet deadlines, and write documentation. Pivoted from the finance industry as an analyst to become a self-taught developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end Development:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS. React, JSX, Next.js.

Other - UX / UI Design, Project Management:

Wireframes, prototypes, usability testing, traditional art.

Agile, Scrum. Figma, Trello. Git, Github.

Certificates/Online Courses:

Meta Front-End Developer Courses

Free Code Camp Certifications: Responsive Web Design, Front End Development Libraries, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures.

CORE SKILLS

- **Communication:** oral and written formal or specified.
- Adaptability: independent and collaborative work, takes initiative to learn new skills to provide additional support.
- Problem Solving: Creative, motivated, and inquisitive keen to identify areas of improvement.

PROJECTS

- Portfolio website React, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS.
- 2D platformer, ladybug jumper game HTML, CSS, Javascript (vanilla).
- Podcast landing webpage HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst - FNZ / Hatch, global wealth platform acquired investment start-up **2020 - 2022**

- **Developed improvements and solutions:** revised customer onboarding processes, banking and trading operations, and related communication. Designed and automated email campaign solutions to gather identification documents for verification.
- **Authored process documentation:** instrumental in training new employees, facilitating auditing and company acquisition, providing clarity around business operations, and streamlining team operations.
- **Managed tight deadlines:** handled reconciliation of FX revenue, completed daily control checks, and frequently liaised with the company broker to book time-critical FX trades.
- **Performed risk and compliance analysis:** reconciliation and verification of transactions, identified capital discrepancies, executed assurance checks.
- **Provided training and reviewed standards for AML/CFT regulations:** (CDD, KYC) responsible collection, evaluation, and use of sensitive data. Maintained records and issue logs to ensure processes were transparent to regulators and external auditors regarding breach and reconciliation recording.

Customer Support Specialist - Trade Me, New Zealand's leading e-commerce marketplace **2018 - 2020**

• Site functionality team. Experience identifying and communicating issues, processes, and solutions to users.

EDUCATION

(BCOM) Victoria University of Wellington

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Commerce in Information Systems and Management, and specialisation in Information Technology Solutions.

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation 2016

Wellington Girls' College

2013 - 2016

Courses taken in web design, graphic design & game design.

Secondary school - NCEA all levels (1, 2, 3) acquired.

VOLUNTEER

Code Club Aotearoa & She Can Code